Guide to the Chad Collection
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
Chad collection
1963-1996
MS 1510
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
1.52
(7 boxes)
The collection consists of printed material relating to the political and economic conditions in Chad, and photographs of Chad.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Transferred from the African Collection Curator.
Associated Materials
African Collection (MS 605); Pamphlet Collection (MS 1351); African Postcard Collection (MS 1575). Manuscripts and Archives, Yale University Library.
Arrangement
The material in the original accession is arranged chronologically. Additions to the collection may vary in arrangement.
Scope and Contents
The collection consists of printed material and photographs relating to the political and economic conditions in Chad.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Chad -- Description and travel; Chad -- Politics and government; Photographs -- Chad
- Original Accession, 1963-1992
  - General information pamphlets; brochures; booklets, [1963?] (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Political organizations: bulletins; journals; newsletters; releases, 1970-1992, undated (Box 1, Folder 2 - 3)
- Additional Material, 1985-1996, undated; Accession 1995-M-172
  - Centre d'Etude et de Formation pour le Développement (CEFOD) [conference bulletins], 1994-1996 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Comité National de Lutte, "Manifeste Politique pour L'Union des Forces Démocratiques", Undated (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Rassemblement pour la Démocratie et la Progrès (R.D.P.) [pamphlets], 1991 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - "Le Tchad en Reconstruction", [1985?] (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Tchad, Republique du, "Ordonnance no. 015/PR/91 Relativeà la création, au fonctionnement et à la dissolution des Partis Politiques", 1991 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Union Démocratique pour le Progrès du Tchad (U.D.P.T), Programme d'Action", 1991 October 15 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Union Nationale pour le Development et le Renouveau (U.N.D.R.), Undated (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Photographs [7 photographs: politics, culture, landscape], Undated (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Additional Material, 1988-1995; Accession 2000-M-014
  - Déby, Idriss, "Some Speeches of the President of Tchad, 1993-1995] (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - La Colombe, 1994 May (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - L'Espoir, Undated (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - La Gazette du Sahel, 1994 August (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Journal Victoire, 1994 August (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Ministère de l'Agriculture and Banque Islamique de Developpement, "Etude de Développement Rural Integre du Lac Fitri", 1988 July (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Mouvement Patriotique du Salut, "Le Tchad depuis le 1er Decembre 1990", 1992 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - La Presse à la Présidence, "Investiture du Président de la République, Son Excellence Al Hadj Hissein Habre", 1989 December 2 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Additional Material, 1961-1987; Accession 2005-M-023
  - General information, 1961 Jan, undated (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - American Council of Voluntary Agencies to Foreign Service, Inc., "Development Assistance Programs of U.S. Non-Profit Organizations", 1977 September (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - "La Bataille de Fada: Les Preuves de la Folie Libyenne", 1987 January (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - "La Bataille de Ouadi-Doum", 1987 April (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Le Héros: Organe de Liason et Information des Forces Armées Nationales Tchadiennes, nos. 8, 10, 11, 1987-1989 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Union Nationale pour l'Indépendance et la Révolution (UNIR) [program guides for second session and second congress], 1985 August 17, 1988 November 23-27 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Images Tchadiennes, Les Grands Evénements, Septembre 1984-Janvier 1986, Undated (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - "Le Tchad aux Tchadiens, Gloire à Nos Combattants" [fabric], Undated (Box 2, Folder 8)
- Additional Material, 1983; Accession 2010-M-099; 0.25; (1 box)
  - Afrique en lutte (bulletin marxiste révolutionnaire afrique noire), 1983 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Additional material, 1982; Accession 2015-M-001
  - Printed material, 1982 (Box 1, Folder 1)